SIEGFRED SAMSON

6, KIKUYU CLOSE, WUSE 2 ABUJA / (+234) 803 619 2916

siegfredsamson@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/siegfred/ | https://github.com/siegfred14

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I am a people-friendly individual who is decision and result oriented, coachable and with good communication skills. As an avid learner, I am comfortably a team player who is largely attracted by the effects of technology on daily affairs, especially as it relates to business, health, community development and human advancement. In addition to my skills and experience in web development, software engineering, sales and marketing, computer engineering, finance and banking, I am also bilingual. I am open to learning new methods to improve myself, my organization and environment by working in your company.

HIGHLIGHTS OF QUALIFICATIONS

- Over 7 years in web development, with experience in both **frontend** and **backend** development.
- 2 years in **computer engineering**, working as a Systems Support Engineer.
- 4 years in Marketing and Public Relations with experience in Digital Marketing, Business Development, Public Speaking, and leading Teams across continents.
- Fluent in English and French, with certified qualifications CLB 8 in International English Language Testing System (IELTS) and niveau B2 in Diplôme d'Etudes en Langue Française (DELF).
- Completed degree in **Computer Science**.
- Versatile in interpersonal relationships and willing to learn.

EXPERTISES

- Application Information Gathering
- Mark Up and Stylesheet Development
- Coding and debugging
- Database and server development
- API development
- Hosting and Deployment
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
- Public Speaking and problem-solving

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer (Web)

Code Clan Nigeria - Nigeria

January 2020 - Present

- Receive requirements and forward to project manager
- Developing mark ups and stylesheets to translate requirements received
- Coding of functionalities using relevant language(s)
- Managing software workflow
- Modifying existing software to rectify errors, upgrade interfaces and designs and refine functionality

Backend Developer (Web) Kwatri Digital Press - Abuja, Feb 2015 – Dec 2019 Nigeria

- Development of web services and APIs
- Design and implementation of data storage solutions
- server-side web application logic
- integration of user interfaces developed by a front-end developers with server side logic
- Optimization of application for speed and scalability
- Conduct tests and perform security and quality control.

Systems Support Engineer OSLA Systems LTD - Abuja, Sept 2012 – Sept 2014 Nigeria

- Analyzing user requirements and design and develop system architecture and specifications.
- Performing research, design, development and integration of computer hardware such as bios, memory, storage and microprocessors
- Evaluating, documenting and optimizing capacity and performance of information and communication system networks.
- Undertaking research, design and development of network architecture of information and communication systems.

Banking Relationship Officer Hedgeworth Microfinance Bank Sept 2009 – Aug 2012 Ltd - Abuja, Nigeria

- Development of banking products.
- Development of sale strategies and promotion techniques to drive up client base and bank deposit volume.
- · Creating credit facilities
- Managing credit facilities from disbursement to liquidation.

Ivianaging credit facilities from dispursement to liquidation.	
EDUCATION	
La langue Française Niveau A1 à B2 Institut Français Nigeria	Feb 2021 - Dec 2021
Bachelor of Science, Computer Science University of Abuja, Nigeria	Oct 2004 - Jan 2009
CERTIFICATES	
Crisis Management London School of Public Relations Limited – London, UK	Apr 2022
International Team Building and Leadership Convention Alliance in Motion Global Inc. – Manila, Philippines	May 2019
Interconnecting Cisco Networking Devices (CCNA 640 – 802) HiiT - Lagos, Nigeria	Apr 2009